This is the fire brigade.
Is anybody here?
Please wait outside.
What's the date of the last letter?
The 9th, as far as I can see.
The door is open!
...no as far as I know.
During the whole time, they had a nurse,
but it's been a while since I last
saw her. My wife has been...
- Did you open the window?
- No.
LOVE
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to
the Théâtre des Champs Elysées.
We ask you to turn off
your mobile phones.
and remind you that all forms of video
and audio recordings are prohibited.
We hope you enjoy the concert.
They used a screwdriver or something
similar. Doesn't look very professional.
- But who would do something like that?
- No idea.
Why someone would try to break in?
Because he wants to steal something.
- From us?
- Why not?
If I come to think about it
three or four people we know
have already been burgled.
What time is it?
Can't we call the caretaker?
I'll do that tomorrow morning.
Don't let this put a damper
on your good mood.
- Or call the police?
- Come, give me your coat.
Imagine if we were lying in bed
and somebody broke in.
Why should I imagine such a thing?
It's terrible.
I think I would die of fright.
I would too.
- Shall we have a drink?
- I'm tired.
I fancy another drink.
Do as you please.
Matilda told me
that in her building
burglars entered the top floor
through the attic.
They simply knocked
a hole into the wall,
cut the most valuable paintings
out of their frames
and disappeared
without leaving a trace.
That's how professionals do it.
Did I tell you that I thought
you looked very pretty tonight.
What's gotten into you?
The semiquavers in the presto
were incredible. What subtlety!
Don't you think?
You're proud of him, huh?
What's the matter.
Nothing.
Next week?
No. Yes.
No, but it would be better to fix this
as soon as possible.
It might give people silly ideas.
And anyway, it's ugly to look at.
At what time?
Yes, okay.
All right.
Will you also bring
the varnish with you?
But at least some primer.
Yes, okay.
Excellent.
Yes.
Well, thank you.
Goodbye. Thank you.
- He's reliable.
- I hope so.
The last time he kept us
waiting for ages, if you remember.
Yes, that's true.
Thank you.
But if I call a regular company, they
let us wait for at least two months.
Oh yeah?
The Frodons had to wait for three days
when their toilet was clogged.
Not exactly pleasant.
The salt cellar is empty.
I don't know if he's going
to bring us the CD today.
Maybe he won't come at all.
We could go to Virgin
this afternoon and buy it.
What do you say?
What's going on?
What's the matter?
Anne?
Cuckoo.
I'm here
Anne.
What's going on?
Anne, what's going on?
What's the matter?
Anne...
Anne, darling, please.
Anne, look at me.
What's the matter?
Anne?
What are you doing?
You left the water running.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Are you completely crazy?
- Is this a joke?
- What?
Is this a joke?
Is this supposed to be a joke?
What joke?
I don't get it.
Why do you talk to me in that tone?
What has gotten into you?
Please, Anne, stop this game,
it's not funny.
What game, for Christ's sake?
What's the matter?
Why did you not react?
- To what?
- To what? Uh, to everything, to me.
- When?
- Just now. A moment ago.
Please, tell me, what's wrong.
I don't know what to say.
You really don't remember
what just happened?
But what did happen?
You were sitting there,
staring into space
and you didn't answer
when I asked you what the matter was.
I took this towel and put it
on your face but you didn't react.
Look, there's still dampness
on your collar.
And when... when was it?
Just now, a couple of minutes ago.
- So?
- So? There's no "so".
I went into the bedroom to get dressed.
I wanted to get help.
- Help?
- Yes.
But then you turned off the tap.
Yes, because you left it on.
I don't understand.
Me neither.
I should call Dr. Bertier.
- Why? What can he do?
- I don't know. Examine you.
I am fine, I am fine.
Please, Anne.
It's absurd, we cannot go on
as if nothing had happened.
But what did happen?
I'm sitting here, having breakfast
and you're telling me things
I don't understand.
Can you explain to me
how the tea towel got here?
No.
- Who turned the tap on?
- You did.
- Oh, you remember that?
- No.
Do you want to torture me?
Leave me in peace.
Don't you think
I'd better call Dr. Bertier?
No!
You know how he is.
Once he's got something into his head,
he has to go through with it.
In the end
everyone was delighted.
Besides, it didn't hurt
our financial situation.
So, we're playing until the 28th,
then we have a ten-day break
then we go to Stockholm for four days
and then to Kuhmo in Finland.
I don't know where that is.
At the North Pole.
Geoff has already been there a few times,
he loves it.
We're playing the "Dowland
Transcriptions" there.
Then we return to London.
What about the children?
Liz is at her boarding school
and John lives his own life. He's 26.
What does he do?
He works.
He is very independent.
We rarely see him.
A bit like Geoff.
They don't really get along.
Geoff wants to advise him on everything.
John doesn't like that at all.
- Is he good?
- Yes, I think so.
He is less impulsive,
but very industrious.
This sounds rather depreciatory.
No. He's just not like Geoff.
He is...
calm, but stubborn.
I think he'll do all right.
The other day he played the solo part
of the Haydn concerto
at the conservatoire's last concert.
It was very good.
Geoff was there
and he congratulated him at the end.
And you?
What do you mean?
Did you both make up?
Oh, you know him.
In September, he discovered his love
for a violinist,
who had been in our ensemble
for many years.
What can I tell you?
It was a huge drama.
She tried to commit suicide.
That scared him.
He returned to me, devoured by remorse.
I've got used to it by now, but...
I feel embarrassed because
the whole ensemble knows about it.
Do you love him?
Yes, I think so.
What about the surgery?
What do you want me to explain?
They made a test,
said the carotid artery was blocked
and that surgery would be necessary.
She was scared.
Totally confused, frightened.
You know
she's always been afraid of doctors.
They said the risk was very low
and that if they didn't operate,
she'd be certain
to have another, more serious stroke.
And what do they say now?
That it didn't go well.
It's one of the 5% that go wrong.
It's pretty upsetting.
Usually at this time, I take a nap.
My blood sugar
is somewhere down in my socks.
- I'm so sorry.
- Yes.
- What can I do for you?
- Nothing.
It was very nice of you to come
despite all of your stress.
No, honestly,
there's nothing you can do.
We'll see how things go
when she's back here in the apartment.
We'll manage all right.
Maybe I'll hire a home health aide,
maybe I'll manage on my own.
We'll see.
We've been through a lot together,
your mother and I.
All this is still a bit new.
It's funny. I don't know if I should
tell you as it might embarrass you
but when I came in earlier
I remembered how I always used to listen
to the two of you making love as a child.
This always reassured me.
It gave me a feeling
that you loved each other
and that we'd always be together.
- Watch your fingers!
- Yeah.
Put this next to the window.
Thank you.
Certainly, sir.
Sorry.
- This is for both of you.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Thank you, Mr. Méry.
If you need anything,
just call downstairs.
- If we can help you in one way or another...
- Right now everything's fine.
I'll let your wife know
as soon as we need anything.
Good to have you back,
Mrs. Laurent.
Yes, thank you, Mr. Méry.
Thank you.
If... If you need anything...
Yes, thank you.
Goodbye then, ma'am.
Welcome home again.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Goodbye, Mr. Méry, thank you.
Where do you want...
In the living room.
Shall I make some tea?
First come sit with me.
- Can you help me into the arm chair?
- Yes, of course.
Come closer.
Put your knees against mine
so I don't slip.
Put your right arm around me.
And lift me up.
And up!
Here.
I'm so glad you're back.
So am I.
- Promise me one thing.
- What?
Please never take me back
to the hospital.
What?
You promise?
- Anne...
- You promise?
- Anne, I'm...
- Don't talk right now.
Don't give me any lectures.
Please.
- What can I say?
- Nothing.
Just don't say anything.
Okay?
Thank you.
Thank you, dear.
- Everything fine?
- Everything is fine.
You don't have to hold my hand
all the time.
I can look after myself,
you know.
And don't feel guilty.
That would be pointless.
And a drag for me too.
- I don't feel guilty.
- That's good.
Go over there now.
I'm not a cripple.
You can easily leave me alone
for two minutes. I won't collapse.
Okay.
Did you buy the new book
on Harnoncourt?
- I've already read it.
- And?
Do you want it?
Shall I get it for you?
Please do.
I don't know where I put it.
- Don't worry. It's not that important.
- Yes it is.
I think I left it...
Ah, here it is!
Nothing like an infallible memory!
I thought I had left it
in the small bedroom
but I had already put it away.
Tidy people just can't help being tidy.
Thank you.
Good, now do something for yourself.
Don't stay here to see
how I hold the book, okay?
Okay.
I'll leave the door open.
Unfortunately the strawberries
were already moldy.
I'll go and get you some fresh ones
tomorrow morning from the market.
My husband will bring you
the Evian water this afternoon.
I'm not supposed to carry anything
heavy. My back, you know.
No problem.
It came to 76.40.
Here's the receipt.
- Your change, 23.60.
- Keep the small change.
Thank you, sir.
Well, I'll be going then.
Call me if you need anything.
I will.
- Is your wife doing well?
- Yes. She's recovering.
That's good.
Give her my regards.
My husband and I are very glad
she's back.
Yes, we are too.
Goodbye, Mrs. Méry, thank you.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Goodbye.
I'll bring you the strawberries
tomorrow around noon, if that suits you.
Yes, fine.
Thank you.
- Can you come here, please.
- Yes.
Some banal love story about a nobleman
and a lower middle class girl
who can't marry
and who then, out of sheer magnanimity,
renounce their love for each other.
In fact, I don't remember the story.
In any case, I remember that I was
completely shaken up when I went out
and that I needed some time
to calm down.
Thank you.
In the courtyard of the house
where grandma lived,
there was a young guy at the window
who asked me where I'd been.
He was a few years older than me.
He was a show-off
who of course really impressed me.
"To the cinema", I said to him.
Because I was very proud grandma had given
me money to go all alone to the cinema.
"What did you watch?"
I started to tell him the story
and as I did,
all the emotion came back.
I didn't want to cry in front of this
guy, but it was impossible.
There I was, in tears in the courtyard,
and I told him the drama till the end.
So? How did he react?
No idea.
He probably laughed at me.
I don't remember.
I don't remember the film either.
But I remember the feelings.
I was ashamed to cry.
But telling him the story made
all my feelings and tears come back,
maybe even stronger than
when I was actually watching the film.
I just couldn't stop.
That's sweet.
Why have you never told me this?
There are still many stories
I've never told you.
Don't tell me you're going to ruin
your image in your old age?
You bet I won't.
But what is my image?
Sometimes you're a monster.
But you're nice.
Can I get you another drink?
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Up to fifteen.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
And fifteen.
- You're okay?
- I'm okay.
Listen to this.
My horoscope.
Motto: You have lots of verve,
but need to be more serious!
Love: High-class conversation
is what you need.
Work: You're motivated again.
But proceed with care.
Health: Loosen up by doing exercises.
It'll give you renewed pizzazz.
You've got only yourself to blame
if you read this nonsense.
Tomorrow afternoon
is Pierre's funeral.
You've got to go.
I fear I must.
Though I don't want to go at all.
Few people like to go to funerals.
Oh, I know a few people who do.
Annette, for instance,
cannot wait to get all dressed up.
- And François, this idiot...
- You're mean.
What would you say
if no one came to your funeral?
Nothing, presumably.
Have you talked to Jeanne
since I went to the hospital?
Does she knows I can't come?
Yes.
Of course.
What did she say?
- She was in shock.
- In what way?
I don't know. What are people like
when they're shocked?
She was speechless,
she couldn't believe it.
I don't know, well, not precisely.
You know I've spoken
to a lot of people since.
I'm sorry.
No.
Please forgive me.
I didn't mean to be unkind.
But what's the point
of talking about it all the time.
Do I talk about it all the time?
No.
I'm sorry.
What...
Why are you back already?
What time is it?
Forgive me, I was too slow.
- Anne...
- Can you wheel me into the living room?
Yes.
You're always good at surprises.
Why did you come home earlier?
I didn't come home earlier.
I took a taxi.
On Saturdays
there's not a lot of traffic.
That's true.
How was the funeral?
Anne...
How was it?
Come on, tell me!
It was rather bizarre.
The priest was an idiot.
A former colleague of Pierre's
came to make a speech
that was embarrassingly emotional.
His former secretary
came with a mini cassette player
and put on "Yesterday" by the Beatles.
You can't imagine.
Everybody turned round
to look at her.
Obviously, it was not planned.
Pierre's grandchildren were there.
Of course, they giggled
as soon as the music began.
Then
the urn was put on a huge stretcher
that was obviously
designed for a coffin,
and we went out into the rain.
They placed the urn
on a small electric cart
that crawled along
for what seemed like an eternity
to the small hole
that they had dug.
Many people got the giggles.
It must have been terrible for Jeanne.
There's no point in going on living.
That's how it is.
I know it can only get worse.
Why should I inflict this on us,
on you and me?
You're not inflicting anything on me.
You don't have to lie, Georges.
Put yourself in my place.
Didn't you ever think
that it could happen to me too?
Of course, I did.
But imagination and reality
have little in common.
- But things are getting better every day.
- I don't want to carry on.
You're making such sweet efforts
to make everything easier for me.
But I don't want to go on.
For my own sake.
Not yours.
I don't believe you.
I know you.
You think you are a burden to me.
But what would you do
in my place?
I don't want to rack my brain
over this.
I'm tired, I want to go to bed.
Hello.
Nice to see you.
I'm sorry to descend upon you like this.
I tried many times to call you
but to no avail.
I'm sorry. I only pick up the phone
when I've stored the caller's number
and I know who's calling.
But come on in.
I was so sorry that I couldn't manage
to come by after the concert.
I was so pleased that you came.
Come with me.
Yesterday my agent called me.
Actually I'm goning to record
an album in June
and I had to pick a location,
a piano.
So I flew into Paris this morning,
and once I was at my hotel, I thought,
I'll just give it a try and drop in.
It's just around the corner.
Very nice.
- This is for your spouse.
- Thank you.
- Isn't she home?
- Yes she is. I'll get her in a minute.
- Have a seat, please.
- I hope I'm not disturbing you.
No, not at all. I'm very happy
to see you. Have a seat.
We were so thrilled by your concert,
my wife and I.
We hoped we'd see you again soon.
Can I can get you something?
- A cup of tea?
- No, thank you.
I'll just put the flowers in a vase
and tell her that you are here.
I'll be right back.
Alexandre, I'm delighted.
How lovely to see you!
Mrs. Laurent!
Lovely to see you too.
Don't get up.
Come on, sit down.
And don't look so serious.
I'm really proud of you.
We were both in raptures
after your concert.
Georges wanted to buy your new CD
the very next morning.
Oh my God! I wanted to bring you one
but then I completely forgot about it.
I left in such a hurry.
- I'll get one today and drop it by.
- No, no, don't worry.
We want to contribute to your success,
even it's only 20 euro.
You have already contributed a lot.
I owe you so much, ma'am.
You owe it to your hard work
and your talent.
Do you remember, when you first gave me
the "Bagatelles" to play?
I was 12 years old.
And in my youthful arrogance
I asked you: "But why the 'Bagatelles'?"
Don't you remember? That day, you really
gave me a piece of your mind.
What has happened to you?
My right side is paralyzed, that's all.
This can happen when you get older.
And how...
Let's talk about something else,
if you don't mind.
Yes.
Don't be offended.
But I want to enjoy the lovely interlude
you've given us with your visit.
Yes, of course.
You haven't told us yet
what's been going on
since the Paris concert.
Well, I was in London
most of the time.
I performed two concerts in Copenhagen,
that was Schubert too.
The "Impromptu", the "Musical Moments".
My whole life revolves
around Schubert at the moment.
Ideally, I would like to record
the complete collection of sonatas.
Though I think I still need
a couple more years for the late ones.
- Could you do me a favor?
- What?
Would play the
"Bagatelle in G Minor" for me?
I haven't played it in a while.
I don't remember it very well.
- If you want, I can give it a try.
- Give it a try.
Okay.
What's the matter?
What are you doing?
Have you completely lost your mind?
I can't believe it.
See what you have done.
Can't you call me
if you need something?
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I am too.
Sorry.
The lamp is broken, too.
Yes?
Who's there?
Anybody here?
Is there anybody here?
Georges, what's the matter?
What's going on?
Calm down, will you.
What was it?
Eva. They're coming on the 12th.
Why?
No idea.
Apparently, she's coming with Geoff.
When is it?
I don't know exactly.
What day is it today?
I'll go and look.
I don't want that.
What?
Geoff doesn't need to come.
It's not necessary.
I don't need any comments
on my predicament.
I can only take his British humor
in small doses.
Dear Mrs. Laurent
and Mr. Laurent.
It was beautiful
and yet sad to see you.
My heartfelt wishes
that things will get better.
With deepest sympathy,
your former pupil, Alexandre.
Stop the CD.
Where are the photo albums?
The photo albums?
I don't know.
In the small bedroom, I think.
Why?
Can you get them for me?
Now?
But why now?
I'd like to look at them.
Please.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
It's beautiful.
What?
Life.
So long.
Long life.
Stop watching me.
I wasn't watching you.
Of course you were.
I'm not that dumb yet.
...the focus will be as much
on the how as on the what.
Benjamin Netanyahu,
is finally granted an official visit
with all the honours:
handshake photo,
joint press conference,
conspicuously demonstrating
the renewal of ties between Isreal...
Israel and the United States.
You're soaked through.
- What do you mean?
- Hang on.
It's no big deal.
Come on.
Wait.
Don't get all worked up.
Calm down, calm down.
...thinking about
whether it wouldn't be better
to invest the money
in an apartment block.
If inflation gets going again,
property is the only sure thing.
Right now,
savings accounts pay 1.75% at best.
That's a good rate already.
Four years ago, Geoff bought
shares for a small amount of money,
and the whole thing collapsed.
So now we're obviously worried.
In the meantime,
other people have had the same idea
and property prices are soaring.
Since I came back from Scandinavia,
I spend my spare time
going through the classifieds.
We'll see.
It takes time.
We'll find something in the end.
I have...
the grandmother...
woman with house...
not...
house then...
money...
I'm... Sorry, Mum,
I don't understand you.
I don't understand
what you say.
yes...
straight away...
it's all...
house sel...
sel...
not...
in two strokes...
so quickly...
God...
it's hard...
say...
house sol...
money gone...
gone...
al... so the... the... the... the... hou... se
Yes.
Whose house?
The house of...
also... grandmother...
grandmother...
Three times a week.
I'm not experienced enough.
We'll see if that's enough.
How much is she asking?
It's paid by the hour.
We'll see.
And her?
Anne?
It's hard to say.
Sometimes I get the feeling she's
totally unaware of the state she's in.
But in the next moment
I feel the opposite.
And what does the doctor say?
He...
She only talks gibberish.
What's going on?
We can't just leave her lying
on her bed like that!
She's unrecognizable!
It's ridiculous!
There's nothing we can do
at the moment.
She's undergoing treatment,
gets medication.
There are no other options
right now.
What does that mean, "no other options"?
Why not put her in the hospital?
She had a second stroke.
Bertier examined her
and felt we could spare her
all the hospital inpatient procedures.
Anyway, they wouldn't keep her.
They'd send her to a care home
with nursing.
What they do in those places,
we can do here.
And she won't be put in a care home.
I promised her that.
Don't you think
you're taking on too much?
Have you got a better idea?
I can't believe that these days
there is not a more effective treatment.
No one's stopping you
from finding out.
I take it you believe me when I say
I love your mother as much as you do.
So please, don't treat me
as if I was a total idiot
incapable of doing the obvious.
I didn't say that.
I'm simply questioning whether what I
see going on here is the best solution.
Don't you want to get
a second opinion?
Stop it, both of you.
Another doctor did come.
He agrees with Bertier.
From Monday, a nurse will come
three times a week.
Is that good enough?
Now can we talk
about something else?
Like what?
a republican awakening by a president
who has secluded himself
in the Élysée Palace for the weekend.
He's cancelled everything,
doors are closed, his schedule is empty.
All that's on his mind right now is to
prepare his appearance on France 2.
This appearance will be in the form of
an interview conducted by David Pujadas
because his previous interview in January
was conducted by TF1's Laurence Ferrari.
France Inter will broadcast a special
programme tomorrow between 9 and 10 p.m.
where we'll analyse
and comment the interview…
...and behind the shoulder. You turn.
And behind the buttocks.
Hold like this, with the elbow.
And we put the nappy on.
Straighten your back.
Straighten it.
Then gently roll back,
straighten your leg.
Could you grap the sheet down there?
I'll help you.
Pull, pull, pull, pull.
Now you pull the diaper.
Like this.
That's it.
And we lie down on the back.
And you put the nappy on
and fasten the tapes.
There, my love,
I hope you like it.
Yes, yes.
I added some peach juice.
I find it tastes quite good.
Come on, Anne, my love,
you've only swallowed three mouthfuls.
I'm sorry.
Mum to the concert...
Yes?
No... no dress...
No dress, mum to the concert.
Mum to the concert...
No!
I'll also wash the other one.
That's it.
Now we only wash off the soap.
Does the temperature suit you?
No? I'm bending you forward.
Don't be afraid, I'm here.
Very well.
...come from 8 till 12
and I'd do 2 until 6, or 3 to 7.
I'll think about it.
She just has to know in time
so she can plan ahead.
Of course. I'll let you know
in the next few days.
Very well.
I have to go now.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- My pleasure.
I'll see you out.
You mustn't take it too seriously.
Usually they always say something.
She might just as well say
"Mum, Mum, Mum".
- It's just mechanical.
- I know.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Goodbye.
I'd like to hire a second nurse.
The two could take turns.
That would make everything
a bit simpler, wouldn't it?
What do you think?
Hurts.
- Please leave them in the kitchen.
- Yes.
I'm back!
Thank you.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
No, thank you.
You've been a big help, Mr. Méry.
It's nothing, sir.
Thanks a lot, sir.
I'll let you know
if I need you again.
With pleasure, sir.
Goodbye.
- May I say something, sir?
- Yes?
My wife and I, we are very impressed
by your handling of the situation.
I take my hat off to you.
That's very kind of you.
Thank you.
Until next time.
- Give my regards to your wife.
- I certainly will.
Hello Eva.
How are you?
Things are fine.
On...
the...
b...
On the bridge...
bridge of A...
of Avignon...
On the bridge of Avignon...
the... the...
- Come on, Anne.
- The bridge!
of Avignon...
vi... vi... vignon... gnon
On the bridge of Avignon
we all dance there,
we all dance there
- Dance!
- On the bridge of Avignon...
- We all dance...
- all... all...
- On the bridge of Avignon
we all dance there,
we all dance there
On the bridge of Avignon
we all dance there in a ring
On the bridge...
dance... dance...
all... all...
There we are.
Now you're all beautiful again.
So everyone will admire you.
That's it.
You want to see?
Wait.
Well?
Aren't we a pretty sight?
Shoo!
As you wish, sir.
I don't know
what you were expecting, but..
I gave up another job
to come and work here.
You should've thought it over before
if you'll need a second nurse or not.
I didn't know then
how incompetent you are.
What's that supposed to mean?
I don't want to discuss it with you.
Anyway, you wouldn't understand.
No one has ever reprimanded me.
Good for you.
How much do I owe you?
780 euro.
I've never had anything like this
happen to me before.
Who do you think you are?
I've been doing this job for years.
I don't need you
to teach me how to do it.
Do you have 20 euro?
- No.
- Then take the 800 and go.
You're a wicked old man.
I feel sorry for you.
I hope from the bottom of my heart
that one day someone treats you
the same way you treat your patients,
and that you too will have no way
of defending yourself.
Now get out.
Get out of here.
Go fuck yourself, you old fart!
Open your mouth, Anne.
Come on, open your mouth.
Anne! Please.
Come on.
Please.
Stop it.
If you don't drink, you'll die.
Is that what you want?
Come on.
Please.
Christ almighty.
You can't force me
to let you die of thirst.
If you persist, I'll call Bertier
and he'll put you in hospital.
They can force-feed you there.
Is that what you want?
I promised to spare you that
but you must help me.
I'm out of my depth.
Come on, Anne.
Drink this, now!
That's it.
Good.
Well, swallow it!
Please, forgive me.
I'm sorry.
- Who's there?
- It's me.
- Eva?
- Yes.
Just a minute.
- Hello.
What was going on?
Nothing.
I was in the toilet.
No, come in.
- Why this unannounced visit?
- What's going on with mum?
Nothing.
What should be going on?
Don't you want to sit down first?
Why are you in Paris?
What's going on with mum?
Why don't you answer the phone?
Since our last conversation, I left
four messages on your answering machine.
Why don't you call back?
Sorry. I didn't listen to it.
Forgive me.
Don't you realize we're worried?
Your worries are no use to me.
No, don't get me wrong.
I'm not criticizing you.
I just don't have the time
to deal with your worries, that's all.
- Dad...
- No, let's stop this conversation.
Your mother is just as could have been
expected: bad the whole time.
She is turning more and more
into a helpless child.
It's sad and humiliating
for her and for me.
And she doesn't want
to be seen in that state.
Even the last time
she did not want you to come.
You two have your own life.
Nothing wrong with that.
But let us have our life too.
Okay?
Dad, what's the matter?
Nothing.
Your visit caught me by surprise.
And I'm annoyed that you show up here
to check that everything's okay.
Who do you think you are?
Stay here, please.
Please!
Mum?
Mum!
Tell me, what's going on?
Have you gone crazy?
Sit down.
I don't want to sit down.
What's going on here?
Nothing's going on. I want to spare
us all a pointless drama.
I presume your mother is asleep.
She sleeps all day.
And then she wakes up at night.
If you really want to,
we'll go and see her in a little while.
Now, sit down.
We do our speech exercises every day,
or we sing together.
Usually I wake up around 5.
At that time, she's still awake.
We change the nappy,
I rub cream on her to avoid bed sores.
Then, around 7, I try to persuade her
to eat and drink.
Sometimes it works, sometimes not.
Sometimes she tells me things
from her childhood.
Or calls for help for hours.
Then, suddenly, she starts giggling.
Or crying.
Nothing of any of that
is worth showing.
You can't forbid me
from seeing her.
No.
It's me, Mum.
Can I do something for you?
Mum.
The tea isn't very hot any more.
But it does make you feel better.
Thanks.
It was silly of me
to lock the door.
I'm sorry.
You took me by surprise.
What's going to happen now?
The nurse comes
three times a week.
Every two weeks Dr. Bertier
and the hairdresser come.
That's what you wanted to know?
No?
Things will go on
as they have done up until now.
They'll go from bad to worse.
Things will go on,
and then one day it will all be over.
You can't go on like this, Dad.
- No?
- No.
What do you suggest?
Can't we have a serious talk,
you and me?
What do you call "a serious talk"?
Do you want to have Mom live with you?
Do you want to pack her off
to a care home?
Is this what you want?
Go on, talk to me seriously!
All long...
Ding dong...
Yes, it swung to and fro.
Yes, yes, to, fro.
You...
Very serious...
Like that.
Yes.
Serious.
Yes, I was very uptight.
Yes.
Up... tight.
It... was... nice.
Hurts.
What's the matter.
Where do you hurt?
What's going on?
Is it the nappy?
Is it full?
Where do you hurt?
It's all right, it's all right.
I'm here.
Everything's fine.
We will...
Do you want me
to tell you a story?
But you must be quiet,
I can't talk too loud.
It wears me out.
When I was little,
well, I wasn't as little as all that,
I think it was
toward the end of primary school,
so I was about 10.
Dad and mum had sent me
to a holiday camp.
They thought it would do me good to
spend the summer with kids my own age.
We were lodged in an old castle
in the midst of the forest.
I think it was in the Auvergne.
I don't remember.
In any case it was the opposite
of what I'd expected.
We had to get up at 6 in the morning
and plunge into a lake.
It was a small lake
not far from the castle.
It was fed by an icy mountain stream.
We had to enter it running,
in a double file.
You know,
I was never very sporty.
They had worked out a programme
to keep us on the go all day,
Probably to nip in... in the bud
any potential pubescent impulses.
But the worst thing was the food.
The third day after our arrival,
there was rice pudding for lunch.
I hate rice pudding.
We sat at long tables in a huge hall.
I didn't want to eat the stuff.
One of the monitors said to me:
"If you don't clear your plate,
you won't get out of here."
So after the meal everybody left,
and I remained alone, in tears.
I had made a secret pact with mum.
I was to write to her every week.
I was to send her a postcard.
If I liked the stay,
I was to draw flowers,
if not, stars.
She kept the card.
It was covered all over in stars.
After three hours,
I was finally allowed to get out.
I went up to my room,
got into bed
I had a fever of over 40 degrees.
It was diphtheria.
I was taken
to the nearest hospital
and sent to quarantine.
Which meant that mum,
when she came to visit me,
could only wave at me
through a window.
At some point I lost that postcard.
It's a pity.
...you won't believe it.
A pigeon came in,
for the second time already,
through the light well.
This time I caught it.
In fact it wasn't difficult at all.
But I set it free again.
I'm almost done.
You can put your shoes on if you want.
Thank you.
Aren't you taking a coat?